Usman Ali Sarwar

Email: maliks_usman786@yahoo.com

Cell: +92.333.8978698

Summary

Prolific full stack web developer with a passion for beating former and metrics. Having nine years of experience in PHP larval and consistently receive high user experience in multiple projects during my career. Passionate in building world class web applications. One of my work received best structure and navigation reviews. I have potential in achieving goals and taking web development organization to next level.

Skills

Language/ Web	PHP, JavaScript, Java, C++, NodeJS, HTML, CSS
Development	
Operating system	Windows/ Linux
Frameworks	Laravel, CodeIgniter, Symfony2, Symfony5, WordPress, Angular CLI, Angular, Vue.JS, ReactJS
Quality assurance	Testing white box and black box
Databases	MongoDB, MySQL, SQL
DevOps	Kubernetes, Docker, PM2
Technologies	

Experience

Micro Data Tech

Senior Web Developer and Team Lead at Micro Data Tech, Lahore, Pakistan August 2017 - Present

Working as team lead on the purchasing system. Managing the team of 4 person. We developed different module to manage the purchase of cars from different auctions.

As a Team Lead

- Working on AKS (Azure Kubernetes Services) and AWS (Cloud 9) and on premises clouds.
- I am working on deployment technologies such as (Kubernetes, Docker and PM2)
- Can create deployment environment on Kubernetes, Docker and PM2
- Build chrome extensions for fetching the data from other web sites
- Build application to manage the to get action data from other web sites using NodeJS, MongoDB and Angular.
- Build application to manage the car loading in container, departure shipping and delivery management using NodeJS, MongoDB and angular

TopDot

Senior Web Developer at TopDot, Lahore, Pakistan August 2014 - July 2017.

Worked as Senior Web Developer. Here I got experience of developing various applications, worked both with a team and independently.

As a Senior Web Developer

- Build various ecommerce websites using PHP Laravel and CodeIgniter frameworks, MySQL and HTML CSS, JavaScript and jQuery
- Build the puzzle game and leaderboard using PHP symfony2 framework, MySQL and JavaScript.
- Build the CMS websites using WordPress

Ejuicy Solutions

Web Developer at Ejuicy Solutions, Islamabad, Pakistan April 2013 - July 2014.

Worked as Web Developer. I worked independently and with team. Got experience of developing various applications with the team member. using PHP Laravel and CodeIgniter frameworks, MySQL and HTML CSS, JavaScript and jQuery.

Gamma Logics Business Solution

Web Developer at Gamma logics Business Solution, Lahore, Pakistan August 2012 – March 2013.

Worked as Web Developer. I worked independently and with team. Got experience of developing various applications with the team member. using PHP Laravel and CodeIgniter frameworks, MySQL and HTML CSS, JavaScript and jQuery.

Education

University of Agriculture BCS/BS, BSCS (HONS) 2012 Computer Science

CGPA: 2.5/4

Sir Seyyed Collage Jaranwala Intermediate/A-Level , F.Sc 2007 Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics

Grade: C+ Govt High School Jaranwala

Matriculation/O-Level, Matric 2004

Computer Science Grade: C

References will be furnished upon request